[Music]
it's been reported that essential oils
show not only antibacterial and
anti-fungal activities but also
anti-viral
activity but it's also been reported
that Bigfoot kept Lumberg Jack as love
slave what does the science
show how about pitting essential oils
against HS V1 the herpes virus that
causes cold sores there's a drug called
acyclovir that helps but now there's
drug resistance strange and said they
were looking for other Alternatives and
say they found that a variety of
essential oils at a concentration of
just 1% could totally suppress the
replication of the virus including tea
tree oil peppermint and on down the list
but this was in a petrie dish what about
in people recurrent cold sorce affect as
many as 20 to 40%
Tetro appeared to work in vitro so they
undertook a randomized placebo
controlled study to evaluate the
advocacy of topically Applied tea tree
oil in the treatment of recurrent cold
Source a 6% tea tree oil gel versus
placebo gel five times a day and the
average healing time seemed to be a few
days shorter and the virus wiped out a
little earlier but none of the
differences between groups reached
statistical significance meaning that
small a difference could have just been
due to chance they blamed the sample
size but maybe t-il just didn't work
it'd be interesting to put lemongrass
oil to the test since it was the only
one still effective at wiping out viral
activity at even 10 times lower a dose.
1% but it doesn't look like that's ever
been done what about warts warts are
caused by viruses too Irish researchers
reported a case of success uccessful
topical treatment of hand warts in a
pediatric patient with t oil a
7-year-old girl with six warts on the
tip of one of her fingers so heavily
clustered as to distort the appearance
of her finger interfering with her
writing and piano lessons she had
undergone the standard costic treatment
where you paint them with acid but they
just came back with a vengeance so her
doctors figured what the heck and
suggested applying straight tea tree oil
and after 5 days all warts had
considerably reduced in size and another
week they were all gone and they didn't
come
back not bad compared to Conventional
wart treatments which can be really
painful whereas in this case the te oil
appeared to work with no side effects
only affecting the warts in contrast to
the standard acid treatments which can
damage the surrounding tissue so they
make an urgent call for randomized
control trials but who's going to fund
that I right it's like pennies per dope
but the reason we particularly like to
see randomized trials for wart
treatments is that they tend to get
better on their own disappearing without
any treatment typically within a year or
two that's why since Antiquity it's been
believe that warts can be removed by
various magical processes you pay some
witch doctor your warts go away on their
own and they take the credit
surprisingly such Charming of warts was
actually put to the test and had no
effect on the warts it's interesting how
they do these studies though like like
this study on whether warts can be
prayed away they used a placebo prayer
so people didn't know whether they were
in the prayed for group or not to
exclude the possibility that they Mind
Over mattered their own wart cure that's
been put to the test too they used a
magic wand secretly connected to a
circuit such that it like tingled when
it wand touched the wart to maximize any
placebo effect and the patients were
mostly unsophisticated Negroes wrote
These 60 scientists yet despite their
purported deep belief in Magic more
warts actually disappeared spontaneously
in the untreated group compared to the
magic wanded ones with no hint of the
mere suggestion of magical cures being
effective I was surprised studies like
this were not only performed but
published in decent journals evidently
publication followed a considerable
debate among the journal editors but
they wanted to keep an open mind they
said but not so open that their brains
fall
[Music]
out